几个世纪以来 神奇水晶的神圣魔法…
For centuries the sacred magic of the Divine Crystal...
一直保佑着我们的世界和人民
...blessed our world and its people.
但不久，其权力的承诺 就给我们的土地带来了战争
But in time the promise of its power brought war to our lands.
路西斯，一个由水晶魔力保护着的 拥有神奇魔法的和平国家
Lucis, a peaceful kingdom of great magic kept safe by the power of the crystal.
尼夫海姆 一个拥有强势军事力量的帝国…
And Niflheim, a military empire of vast machinery...
凭借它的魔击术变得日益强大
...made strong by the might of its Magitek.
两国之间的战斗旷日持久
Long has war raged between the two.
（路西斯退出）
随着时间的推移 尼夫海姆凭借其不可摧毁的魔力…
As the years passed, Niflheim marched on nearby nations...
向邻国一步步挺进
...driven by its unsurpassed technology.
为了自我防御 路西斯建立起一座魔法城墙…
To defend itself, Lucis raised a magical wall...
墙的力量来自于水晶本身
...the strength of which comes from the crystal itself.
王都因索莫尼亚 路西斯的最后堡垒…
Insomnia alone, the crown city and last bastion of Lucian defense...
多年来免受尼夫海姆帝国的侵略
...remained beyond Niflheim reach for many years.
在不断升级的战事中…
Amid the escalating war...
路西斯的王子诺克提斯 来到戴涅布莱国…
...Prince Noctis of Lucis had come to Tenebrae...
为了他的病痛来寻求医治
...to seek healing for a grievous injury.
他与他的父王雷吉斯一行远道而来
He made the long journey together with his father, King Regis.
母后、哥哥，还有我 戴涅布莱国的皇室成员…
Mother, brother, and I, the royalty of Tenebrae...
一同欢迎了他们的到访
...had all welcomed their visit.
就在那时 战火在各个地方同时开始了
It was then that the fires came, everywhere and all at once.
转瞬之间 整个戴涅布莱国火光遍地
In a mere instant, the whole of Tenebrae was ablaze.
雷吉斯！
Ravus!
母亲！
Mother!
格拉乌卡将军
General Glauca.
尼夫海姆帝国的进攻 是针对来访的路西斯皇室成员的
The Niflheim attack was an attempt on the lives of the visiting Lucian royalty.
诺克提斯！
Noctis!
求你了 救救我们！
Please. Help us!
雷吉斯国王！
King Regis!
露娜弗雷亚…
Lunafreya....
露娜！
Luna!
从那天起直到今天…
From that day until this day...
戴涅布莱国 一直被尼夫海姆帝国的铁拳控制…
...Tenebrae has been gripped in the iron fist of Niflheim...
宣誓与路西斯为敌
...sworn enemy of Lucis.
（十二年后…）
雷吉斯组织了强大的军队 来抵御尼夫海姆帝国的威胁
King Regis assembles a force of mighty warriors to combat the imperial menace.
王者之剑 他们凭藉着本国魔法赋予的力量…
Dubbed the Kingsglaive, they fight relentlessly against Niflheim...
与尼夫海姆帝国军队英勇作战
...empowered by the magic of their sovereign.
所有分队 坚守城墙
All units, move to secure the Wall.
如果他们打进来 我们就完了
If they break through, we're done.
怎么这么久 克劳？
What's the hold-up, Crowe?
克劳！ 情况怎么样？
Crowe! Status?
快要到了
Almost there.
不！
No!
我需要支援，东墙已经失守 皮尔纳，你能回复我吗？
I need help. East wall's going down. Pelna, can you get to me?
路西斯让我们这些难民干这个…
Lucis isn't paying us refugees enough...
就给我们这点儿钱
...for this.
这算公平吗？
How is this fair?
尼克斯 我欠你一条命
Nyx, I owe you one.
你还有其他所有人
You and everyone else.
我们东侧需要支援 尼克斯，你在哪儿？
We need support on the east flank. Nyx, where are you?
我马上到
I'm on my way.
皮尔纳，快撤退 和其他人会合
Pelna, fall back and regroup with the others.
小心使用魔法 大英雄
Go easy on the magic, hero.
家人都在等你回来
You got people waiting for you back home.
我值得等待
I'm worth the wait.
看我大显身手
Show-off.
小心后面，利波特斯 敌人更多了
Watch your back, Libertus. We got more incoming.
我们坚持不了多久了
We ain't gonna last much longer.
克劳！
Crowe!
是的！
Yes!
所有剑队队员撤退 重复，所有剑队队员撤退！
All Glaives, fall back. Repeat, all Glaives fall back!
放出魔鬼
Release the daemon.
我们无法打败魔鬼 我要求全体撤退
We can't take down that daemon. I'm ordering a full retreat.
活着回来 这是命令
Get back here alive. That's an order.
为了家园
For hearth and home.
所有分队，撤回提取点 支援回程
All units, fall back to the extraction point. Support is inbound.
尼克斯！ 我们必须离开这里
Nyx! We have to get out of here.
-尼克斯，这是命令！ -是的
-Nyx! We have orders! -Yeah.
救命！
Help!
尼克斯！
Nyx!
那个笨蛋
That idiot.
尼克斯！
Nyx!
克劳 我们得走了
Crowe. We gotta move.
你在开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
你知道我最受不了这个
You know I ain't got the stomach for this crap.
你能走吗？
Would you rather walk?
快 就像是家乡的加拉哈峡谷
Come on. Just like Galahd Canyon back home.
利波特斯！
Libertus!
卢彻 报告
Luche, report.
皇室部队看来正在撤退 长官
The imperial forces look to be withdrawing, sir.
我想我又欠你的情了
Guess I owe you another one.
我会把它放在你的标签上的
I'll put it on your tab.
你好好休息吧 好吗？
You just try and get some rest, all right?
你抵抗了撤退的命令
You disobeyed a direct order to retreat.
为了家园 是吗，长官？
For hearth and home, right, sir?
只要我还有一口气 我就会谨遵命令
As long as I got strength in my body, I obey that order.
别傻了 尼克斯·乌尔里克
Don't fool yourself, Nyx Ulric.
无论你有何种力量 都是来自于国王的
Whatever strength you have is on loan from the king.
没有他 你一无是处
You are nothing without him.
等候你的处理安排吧
Await details of your reassignment.
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Majesty.
尽管敌人获得了胜利
Despite their victory all but assured.
一次突然而且莫名其妙的撤退
A sudden and inexplicable retreat.
我们依然置身于危险之中 陛下
We are at risk nonetheless, Your Majesty.
我们不知道他们什么时候会回击
We cannot know when they will strike again.
陛下 西门有消息
Your Majesty, word from the West Gate.
一名自称是敌国使者的人 请求见您
A man claiming to be an envoy of the empire requests an audience.
尼夫海姆的使者求见 陛下
The envoy from Niflheim awaits without, Your Majesty.
您好
Hello there.
您好！
Hello!
很高兴见到您…
Good day to you...
还有您
...and you.
很高兴见到你 路西斯人们
Well met, my dear Lucians.
尼夫海姆竟然如此毫无顾虑…
Has Niflheim grown so bold...
派他们的宰相亲自做使者？
...that they send the chancellor himself as envoy?
而且只身一人前来？
And under no guard, at that?
能被伟大的雷吉斯国王认出来 真是我的荣幸
It is an honor to be recognized by the great King Regis.
而且允许我站在大堂之上 做自我介绍
Yet permit me to stand on ceremony and introduce myself nonetheless.
我是阿登·伊祖尼亚 尼夫海姆的宰相…
Ardyn Izunia, Chancellor of Niflheim...
愿意为您效劳
...at your humble service.
我在最吉利的日子来拜访您…
And I come to you on this...
是为了呈上和平协议
...most auspicious of days to offer terms of peace.
和平？
Peace?
您肯定猜到了…
As you no doubt surmised...
我们最近的作战方案 并不是有计谋的撤退
...that recent maneuver of ours was no strategic retreat.
请叫它…
Call it...
一次邻国的示好
...a gesture of imperial goodwill.
正如你一样 我们最大的希望就是…
Like you, we wish nothing more...
为这场豪无意义的战争画上句号
...than to bring a swift end to this senseless war.
果真如此吗？
Is that so?
千真万确
It is, indeed.
但是我们要求你们完全的顺服
And we require but a singular compliance.
为了拯救你们的王都因索莫尼亚
Save your grand Insomnia here.
路西斯必须割让所有的领土
Lucis must forfeit all territories to Niflheim rule.
因索莫尼亚！
Insomnia!
路西斯王国皇冠上的明珠
The jewel in the crown of the Lucian kingdom.
对了 我怎么能够忘记
How foolish of me to forget.
还有一件小事
There is just one more trivial thing.
有关于您的儿子
It concerns your son.
路西斯王国的王子诺克提斯…
The fetching Prince Noctis of Lucis...
还有戴涅布莱国的美丽公主 露娜弗雷亚…
...and the fair Princess Lunafreya of Tenebrae....
他们要结为夫妇
They are to be wed.
您看起来很苦恼 尊敬的陛下
You seem vexed, Your Highness.
我向您保证 公主一直以来都敬重您…
I assure you, the princess still holds you in the highest regard...
这十二年来一向如此
...as she has done all these 12 long years.
不知道有没有人告诉你…
Don't know if anyone's told you...
但是我们从来不容忍 不服从命令的人
...but we don't take kindly to insubordination around here.
你自己好好看看吧
Do yourself a favor, take a look around.
这就是百年和平的景象
This is what a hundred years of peace looks like.
这种和平仅仅靠着一堵墙维持
It's a lasting peace made by the Wall and the Wall alone.
看见了吧 我们不需要你们这些外来移民…
See, we don't need any of you immigrants...
上蹿下跳 充英雄
...jumping around, playing war hero.
嘿！ 今天一战不顺利吧，剑员？
Hey! Rough day on the gate, huh, Glaive?
你这个混蛋 是你害的我们被困在那儿
You jerk. It's your fault he got stuck there.
-这样欢迎大英雄可不好 -你这一身装扮也不好
-Not a very nice welcome for a big hero. -Not a very nice outfit for one, either.
这样穿能突出我的眼睛
I think it brings out my eyes.
这里面放了什么东西？
What'd you put in this?
吃起来就像是陆行鸟的大便
Tastes like a chocobo turd.
闭上你的臭嘴！
Hey, shut your trap!
这儿可不是加拉哈 我们这儿的人都喜欢这个
This ain't Galahd. That's the way folks around here like it.
好吧，我真高兴看到你 情愿出卖我们的传统，只为多赚点钱
Oh, well. I'm glad to see you're willing to sell out our heritage for a few extra gil.
利波特斯 你感谢尼克斯的救命之恩了吗？
Hey, Libertus. You thank Nyx for saving your life yet?
得了吧，克劳 我和尼克斯谁跟谁呀
Oh, come on, Crowe. Nyx and I are too close for that.
他帮我，我帮他 一向如此
He helps me, I help him. That's the way it's always been.
看来你从别的地方获得帮助了 是吗？
Looks like you got a little help from something else, huh?
我需要所有可能的帮助
I need all I can get.
为了温暖！
For hearth!
-还有家园 -还有家园
-And home. -And home.
尼克斯，新任看门人 新工作怎么样？
So, Nyx the Gatekeeper. How's the new post treating you?
简直棒极了 你们肯定会喜欢的
Oh, it's amazing. You guys would love it.
看大门真是太棒了
The gate watch are real sweethearts.
是的 没错
Yeah, right.
我们都知道 他们恨我们这些外来人胜过一切
We all know they hate us outsiders more than anything.
他们除了恨我们 没有事情做
So bored they got nothing better to do.
无聊也没那么糟
Boredom's not so bad.
至少意味着和平
Means there's peace, at least.
为了了解无聊的感受 我愿意为加拉哈人民再战上百次
I'd fight a hundred more wars for Galahdans to know boredom.
随便你
Fight all you want.
只是不要把命丢了
Just don't go dying yet.
我还是欠你的
I still owe you.
欠你很多
A lot.
王者之剑没有了英雄 该何去何从呢？
Where would the Glaive be without its hero?
我们喝酒的时候 你能不能别说这些？
Can you not talk like this while we're drinking, please?
我们刚刚把敌人打得落花流水 不是吗？
We just sent the Niffs running with tails between their legs, right?
他们并不是逃跑了 他们只是在耍我们
They weren't running from us. No, they were toying with us.
别这么扫兴，卢彻 我们都知道发生了什么
Stop being such a buzzkill, Luche. We all know what happened.
你们知道他们派出了使者 来到堡垒吗？
Did you know they sent an envoy to the Citadel after that?
为了什么？ 向我们投降吗？
What for? To offer their surrender?
-更像是命令我们 -什么？
-More like demand ours. -What?
命令？ 去他们的！
Demand? My ass!
不可思议吗？ 好好想想吧
No? Think about it.
敌人已经把路西斯逼到了绝境
The empire's got Lucis on its last legs.
现在正是发出命令的绝佳时机
It's the perfect time to make demands.
我们输定了 陛下
We are losing this war, Your Majesty.
路西斯不能光靠王者之剑
Lucis cannot rely on the Kingsglaive alone.
接受停战协议会是我们最好的选择
Accepting the truce may be our best course of action.
你这样说完全忘记了我们的新墙
You speak of matters beyond the New Wall.
只要新墙还在 我们就不需要什么停战协议
We have no need of a truce here, so long as it stands.
即使处境变得更糟 我们还有旧墙
And if our position worsens, we still have the Old Wall.
是的 但是停战协议可以停止一切战争
Yes, but this truce will end the fighting altogether.
如果我们肯妥协…
If only we could compromise--
妥协是不明智的
Compromise is unwise.
我们不知道尼夫海姆的真正动机
We know nothing of Niflheim's true intentions.
别傻了 城墙远非坚不可摧
Do not fool yourselves. The Walls are far from impenetrable.
我们的选择所剩无几
The paths left to us are few.
新墙从王座上吸取力量
The New Wall draws its power from the throne.
如果国家需要 我还可以再支撑它几年
I am able to sustain it for some years yet, if the kingdom requires it.
但是敌国丞相说了一件事实
But the chancellor spoke one truth, if only one.
我们都老了 旧城墙也…
We are old, and the Old Wall....
我不能以一只虚弱的手来指挥旧墙…
I cannot command the Old Wall with a weakened hand...
我也没有力量再掀起反攻的战斗了
...nor do I have the strength to muster an offensive to turn the tide on this war.
请做出最后决定吧 陛下
Then let the choice be made, Your Majesty.
我们要做什么？
What are we to protect?
救命 母亲！
Help Mother!
你为什么从来没有这样不走运过？
How come you never lose your lunch like that?
这些都讲不通
Just doesn't add up.
这是一种古老的艺术 是皇室的秘密
Here's this ancient art, secret of the royal family and all that.
利波特斯！ 尼克斯！
Libertus! Nyx!
你们都过来 瞧瞧这个
Come here, guys, you gotta see this.
今天的国会显得很忙碌…
Things were hectic in the capital today...
因为路西斯政府宣布完全接受…
...as the Lucian government announced full acceptance...
被某些人批评为单方面的…
...of what some are criticizing as the unilateral peace terms...
由尼夫海姆宰相 伊祖尼亚提出的和平条件
...proposed by Chancellor Izunia of Niflheim.
停战协议规定 路西斯的所有领土…
The signing of the truce will see power over all Lucian territories...
将归尼夫海姆帝国统治 除了王都因索莫尼亚
...transferred to the empire, with the sole exception of Insomnia.
作为交换，尼夫海姆保证 因索莫尼亚及其居民的安全…
In return, Niflheim guarantees the safety of Insomnia and its citizenry...
以及停止一切敌对行为…
...as well as a cessation to all hostilities...
为这场旷日持久的战争画上句号
...bringing a decisive end to this long and bitter war.
我们参加的所有战斗 一切都是徒劳无功
All that fighting we did. All for nothing.
队员们 报告室集合
Glaives. Assemble in the briefing room.
马上
Now.
国王已经发言 你们也已经听到了
The king has spoken, and you have heard.
所有城墙之外的领地 都将割让给尼夫海姆帝国
All lands beyond the Wall are to be relinquished to the empire.
没有幸存的领地吗？
Will no regions be spared?
-没有 -但是你的家乡也在其中呀！
-None. -But your home's out there too!
我知道
It is.
国王为什么这么做？
Why would the king do this?
因为这样可以结束该死的战争
Because it'll end this damn war.
-克劳 -长官！
-Crowe. -Sir!
做好准备 你要潜入戴涅布莱国
Prepare to deploy. You're being sent to infiltrate Tenebrae.
戴涅布莱国 长官？
Tenebrae, sir?
任务细节属于机密
Mission details are classified.
三十分钟后 到我的办公室接受任务…
Report to my office for briefing in 30 minutes.
还有 尼克斯…
And, Nyx....
你不用再守城门了
You're off the West Gate.
你被重新调回堡垒守卫
You've been reassigned to the castle guard.
就这些
That is all.
这就是你要说的吗 卢彻？
So this is what you were talking about, Luche?
你听到长官说的了
You heard the captain.
-这又不是我们能决定的 -我们不能决定？
-This wasn't our decision to make. -Not ours to make?
那里是我们的家园！ 我们的亲人！
Those are our homes out there! Our people!
你不会就这样抛弃他们吧？
You're just gonna go along and abandon them?
如果我们不妥协…
If we don't go along with them...
尼夫海姆帝国就会把 因索莫尼亚变成地狱
...the empire will unleash all hell on Insomnia.
-那我们就把他们也扔进地狱！ -别激动，别激动
-We'll unleash it right back at them! -Easy, easy.
他不是敌人
He's not the enemy.
你不明白吗？
Don't you get it?
我们对他们来说 不值一提
We're nothing to them.
胆小如鼠 躲在城墙后面
Rats, snuck in from beyond the Wall.
当然了 他们会利用我们…
Sure, they had a use for us...
因为他们觉得我们可以使用魔法
...when they realized we could work their magic.
所以他们把我们 从那些老鼠当中挑出来…
So they handpicked us from all the other rats out there...
让我们蚕食他宝贵的皇室能力
...and just let us nibble away at his royal majesty's precious power.
但是一旦战争结束…
But as soon as this war's all over...
我们就要回到下水道了
...it's back to the sewers for all of us.
连你也是 英雄
That means you too, hero.
你那么想家，利波特斯 为什么不和尼克斯一起回去呢？
You missing home so much, Libertus, why don't you and Nyx head on back?
我肯定尼夫海姆会张开双臂欢迎你的
I'm sure Niflheim will welcome you with open arms.
你的家乡也在那儿
You've got a home out there too.
还是说你已经忘了？
Or did you forget?
该死！
Damn it!
我不会袖手旁观的
I'm not gonna let it end like this.
据说民众的情绪很好 陛下
It is said sentiment amongst the people is favorable, Your Majesty.
大部分人都欢迎这样的和平
Most all will welcome this peace.
如果你没有亲耳听到他们的声音…
If you yourself have not heard their voices...
你怎么能知道他们的真实想法？
...how can you claim to know their hearts?
去戴涅布莱国的任务怎么办 陛下？
What of the mission to Tenebrae, Your Majesty?
这样的秘密行动是否明智？
Is such clandestine action wise?
如果被发现 这只会激起尼夫海姆帝国的不满
If discovered, it will only serve to provoke the empire.
在合约签署之前 尼夫海姆帝国一直是我们的敌人
The empire remains our enemy until the treaty is signed.
只要我们还在战争中…
So long as we are at war...
陛下就坚持要领先一步
...His Majesty intends to remain one step ahead of them.
当然
Of course.
发卡？ 我觉得你应该不喜欢这种东西
A hairpin? I didn't think you were into that kind of thing.
不是给我的 是给公主的礼物
It's not for me. It's a gift for the princess.
但是不要张扬 要保密
But keep that quiet. Nobody's supposed to know.
是叫我的
Well, that's me.
多加小心
Watch your back out there.
我知道你不喜欢听 但是你就像一个…
I know you're sick of hearing it, but you're like a little--
你的小妹妹 我知道，我都听烦了
Little sister to you. Yeah, I am sick of hearing it.
要保证完完整整地回来 好吗？
Just make sure you come back in one piece, all right?
你都不是一个完整的人
Says the guy in two pieces.
（戴涅布莱国的曾经属地）
露娜弗雷亚公主 我把后门打开了
Lady Lunafreya, I have left the rear gate open.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你必须要走吗？
Must you go?
是的
Yes.
那就快一点儿
Then go quickly.
我记得我没有允许过你离开这里 露娜弗雷亚
I do not recall granting you permission to leave your quarters, Lunafreya.
雷夫斯
Ravus.
在去路西斯之前 你不准再离开这个房间
You are not to leave this room again until the journey to Lucis.
这是为了你好
It is for your own good.
为了我？
My own good?
到底发生了什么？
What is truly going on here?
尼夫海姆帝国逼我和诺克提斯结婚 有什么用意？
What cause does the empire have to see me wed to Noctis?
他们要和解 而你们的联姻就是橄榄枝
They have offered a peace, and your marriage is the olive branch.
你想要我相信吗？
You expect me to believe that?
我不在乎你信不信
What you believe does not concern me.
我在乎的是 你偷偷溜出去…
What does concern me is you sneaking off...
告诉你母亲的杀手 一些你自己编造的故事
...to go tell our mother's killer about some plot you've dreamt up.
你憎恨雷吉斯国王是不对的
You are wrong to hate King Regis.
是尼夫海姆杀了母亲 不是他
Niflheim killed Mother, not him.
他们杀了母亲 让你成了他们的哈趴狗
They murdered her and made you their lapdog.
完毕
It's done.
在等待停战的期待当中 喜悦的气氛已经风靡全城…
An air of jubilation has swept the city in anticipation of the coming armistice.
在和平协议正式生效前 仅仅只剩三天时间了…
With only three days remaining until the peace is officially signed into effect...
居民们踊跃的走上街头 表示…
...throngs of citizens have taken to the streets to show....
（-路西斯退出 -尼夫海姆袭击加哈拉）
（和平协定 三天后生效）
路西斯需要你们 年轻的战士们
Lucis needs your strength, young warriors.
我们不需要你们这些外来移民
We don't need any of you immigrants.
（雷吉斯国王强迫“王者之剑” 进入加哈拉废墟？）
不论你有何种能力 都是来自于国王
Whatever strength you have is on loan from the king.
-没有他，你一无是处 -尼克斯，救救母亲
-You are nothing without him. -Nyx, help Mother.
瑟琳娜 趴下
Selena, get down.
尼夫海姆的外交官们一波波涌进城市
--and the waves of imperial diplomats entering the city.
她是公主？ 你确定吗？
The princess? Are you certain?
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Majesty.
她跟随最后一些帝国来者们 进入了城市
She was amongst the last of the imperial contingent to enter the city.
上车
Get in.
我现在要去报告情况了 长官
I'm reporting to my post now though, sir.
新任务
New orders.
快 我们要去接一位公主
Come on. We've got a princess to pick up.
车不错 长官
Nice ride, sir.
这是王子的车
It belongs to the prince.
我们接他出了城
We've taken him outside the city.
他不是要准备婚礼吗 长官？
Doesn't he have a wedding to plan, sir?
别再叫我“长官”了
Cut the "sir" crap.
国王有自己的打算
The king has a plan of his own.
诺克提斯王子和露娜弗雷亚公主 要在城外很远处见面
Prince Noctis and Princess Lunafreya are to meet far from Insomnia.
那她来这儿干什么？
What's she doing here then?
使局面更复杂
Complicating things.
我们派克劳去找公主 并且把她护送出戴涅布莱国
We sent Crowe to find the princess and escort her out of Tenebrae.
我们还在追查问题出在哪儿
We're still trying to figure out what went wrong.
我知道你对战争的看法 那你怎么看这场和平呢？
So I know what you think about this war, but what do you think about this peace?
放弃自己的家乡 你高兴吗？
You happy giving up your home?
这是国王的决定 因为他重用了我，我欠他的
It's the king's decision. I owe him for taking me in.
我很幸运 加哈拉有很多人没有这么幸运
I was lucky. There are people in Galahd who weren't.
他们需要我
And they need me.
你要回去吗？
So you're going back?
没有国王的魔法 你能怎么帮他们？
What good will you be without the king's magic?
是的 总是想要拯救别人
Yeah, always wanting to save somebody.
我明白了，听我说 你这样不能赢得战争
I get it. Believe me. But it doesn't win wars.
这不只是愿望
It's not just wanting.
这不只是关于我
It's not just me.
利波特斯才是你需要担心的人
Libertus is the one you need to worry about.
如果局势变糟 他肯定会回去
He'll go back if things gets worse.
糟糕的还在后面呢
The worst is yet to come.
（西门，四公里 15号出口）
你知道你要阻止的人是谁吗？
Do you have any idea who you're stopping?
把门打开 或许明天你还能保住工作
Open this gate now, and maybe you'll have a job tomorrow.
-这是国王的命令 -你确定你想要挑起…
-King's orders. -Are you sure you want to risk...
外交争端吗？
...a diplomatic issue now, of all times?
我是露娜弗雷亚·诺克斯·芙尔累 公主的私人护卫…
I am the personal escort of Lady Lunafreya Nox Fleuret...
戴涅布莱国前任公主…
...princess of the former Tenebrae and--
我们国家广受爱戴的准新娘
And our kingdom's beloved bride-to-be.
欢迎来到主权管辖区 从现在开始，由我们一手接管
Welcome to sovereign jurisdiction. We'll take care of things from here.
-不还意思，德劳托斯长官 -送公主去往城堡
-Forgive me, Captain Drautos. -See Her Highness to the castle.
我完全不知道你… 我不清楚…
I had no idea that you-- I wasn't made aware of any--
-对不起，多谢 -不，你…我必须…
-Excuse me. Thank you. -No, you-- I must--
我必须… 我必须先跟我的上司解释清楚
I must-- No, I have to clear it with my superiors first.
公主殿下
Your Highness.
戴涅布莱国的公主殿下 露娜弗雷亚
Her Royal Highness, Princess Lunafreya of Tenebrae.
好久不见了 陛下
It has been a long time, Your Majesty.
是呀
Yes.
太久了
Far too long.
诺克提斯王子不在这儿 是吗？
Prince Noctis isn't here, is he?
是的，亲爱的公主 他不在这儿
No, my dear. He is not.
我太老了 不能应战
I am too old to fight this war.
我别无选择 只能接受帝国的要求
I have no choice but to receive the empire and accept their treaty.
即便如此…
Even so...
我还是希望婚礼可以在别的地方举行 安全的地方
...I had hoped to hold the wedding elsewhere, somewhere safe.
我派出一名剑队成员去找你 但是…
I sent one of my Glaive to see you there, but--
现在还不晚
It is not too late.
我可以安派人护送你
I can ready an escort.
求你了 去找我的儿子
Please, go to my son.
不
No.
不管我去哪儿 帝国都会跟着我
Wherever I go, the empire will follow.
这样只会将王子置于更危险的境地
It would only place the prince in greater danger.
我的职责是保护王子 帮助他完成他的使命
It is my duty to protect the prince and see his destiny fulfilled.
十二年的时间没有改变我的初衷
These 12 years have not changed that.
那你的命运吗？
And what of your destiny?
我的职责就是我的命运 陛下
My duty is my destiny, Your Majesty.
我已经准备好迎接一切了
I'm prepared to accept whatever may come to pass.
你觉得怎么样？
So, what do you think?
这些领土很快都会变成帝国的了
All these lands will be imperial soon.
估计那些尼夫海姆人开始发号施令时 局面会变好吗？
Reckon things will get better when them Niffs start calling the shots?
没有一点儿好东西
Not one damn bit.
我才不管是谁掌权呢
Don't matter who's calling the shots.
只要他们是从那面墙后面来的…
Long as they're calling them from behind the Wall...
这里的情形就不会有好转
...ain't nothing gonna change around here.
过来这儿
Get over here.
好吧
All right.
这是一只手！
That's a hand!
我打赌这是一场欢乐的团聚？
I trust the reunion was a happy one?
这些年来 她一直都是尼夫海姆的人质吗？
Has she been a hostage of Niflheim all this time?
她是和平的象征 我就知道这些
She is a symbol of the peace. That's all I'm told.
听起来不像
Doesn't sound like it.
听起来她的到访 目的远非如此
Sounds like she's here for something much bigger than that.
你的任务是保护她
Your orders are to protect her.
不要观察她，不要倾听她 更不要去思考
Not to look, not to listen, not to think.
明白吗？
Understood?
我是德劳托斯
Drautos.
是的 汇报
Yes, report.
给我让开路 里面是我的朋友，该死
Get the hell out of my way. That's my friend you got in there, damn it.
先生，在检查结束之前 你不能进去
Sir, you can't go in until the examination has ended.
什么检查？ 到底是怎么回事？
What examination? What the hell's going on?
嘿，放松点儿 伙计
Hey, take it easy, big guy.
克劳一回来 这些混蛋就把她推进了这里
These bastards rushed Crowe in there the moment she got back.
现在他们不让我进去看她
And now they won't let me in to see her.
等一下
Wait.
克劳的私人物品
Crowe's personal effects.
你看着处理吧
Do with them as you see fit.
你到底派她去执行什么任务？
So, what kind of mission did you really send her on?
没有一个剑队成员 会在执行普通的护送任务时送命
No Glaive winds up dead on a standard escort.
停战不会影响进行详尽的调查
I'll see the armistice does not interfere with a full investigation.
她是一名优秀的战士
She was a good soldier.
她不会白白送死的
Her death will not go unanswered.
造化弄人呀 对吗？
What a life, huh?
她是个孤儿
She was brought up an orphan.
从她的村庄跑出来
Run out of her village.
我还记得第一次见到她
I still remember the first time I saw her.
骨瘦如柴的小家伙…
Scrawny little thing...
浑身脏兮兮的
...all covered in dirt.
全世界没有一个朋友
Not a friend in the world.
但是那双眼睛…
But those eyes....
该死
Damn.
那双眼睛里有故事
There was something about those eyes.
她不应该就这样死去
She deserved better.
我愿意为此付出一切…
And I would've done anything to give it to--
利波特斯 等一下
Libertus, wait.
克劳死的时候是一名剑队成员
Crowe died a Glaive.
你可以好好战斗 来纪念她
You can still honor her by fighting as one.
你有时候比我还蠢 你知道吗？
You're dumber than me sometimes, you know that?
你还不明白吗？
Don't you get it?
路西斯害死了克劳
Lucis killed Crowe.
回到城堡
Go back to the castle.
告诉国王 把弱者扔给饿狼是得不到和平的
Tell the king there's no peace to be had from throwing the weak to the wolves.
从现在开始 我要孤身作战
I'll fight my own fight from here on out.
再见了 英雄
See you around, hero.
一个发卡？
A hairpin?
我觉得你不会喜欢这种东西的
I didn't think you were into that kind of thing.
这不是给我的 是给公主的礼物
It's not for me. It's a gift for the princess.
（签字仪式之夜）
真是一场盛大的欢迎仪式 雷吉斯国王
A most grand reception, King Regis.
您荣耀了所有的尼夫海姆人
You honor all of Niflheim.
荣耀是属于我们的 艾尔德卡普特国王
Oh, the honor is ours, Emperor Aldercapt.
您远道而来 大驾光临
You have ventured far to grace us with your presence.
尽微薄之力而已
It was the very least I could do.
对于我们两国而言 明天将会是历史性的一天
Tomorrow will be an historic day for both our nations.
您的因索莫尼亚真是一个奇迹
And your Insomnia is truly a marvel.
相比之下 我本国的城市黯然无光
My own cities pale in comparison.
我祈祷这次拜访能够满载而归
I pray we are able to take away much from this visit.
你好
Hello.
我想今天我们没有正式认识一下
I am afraid we were never properly introduced yesterday.
恐怕您还要等一下，公主殿下 我正在执勤
I'm afraid it's going to have to wait, Your Highness. I'm on guard duty.
那就更没有比这里更安全的地方了
Then surely there's no safer place for me to be.
我能知道你的名字吗？
May I ask your name?
尼克斯 尼克斯·乌尔里克
Nyx. Nyx Ulric.
我还有一件事要问你 尼克斯·乌尔里克
There is something else I wish to ask you, Nyx Ulric.
雷吉斯国王说 他派出了你们的一名队员去找我
King Regis said he sent one of your order to come find me.
我想要亲自谢谢他
I should like to offer my thanks in person.
我到哪儿才能找到这名英勇的士兵？
Where might I find this brave soldier?
我不是…
Oh, I did not--
-我很抱歉 -不必
-I am so sorry. -Don't be.
给你
Here.
她拿着这个
She was carrying this.
原本是要给你的
It was meant for you.
给我？
For me?
拿着吧
Keep it.
她肯定希望你能戴上它
She would've wanted you to have it.
我会一直随身带着的
I will carry it with me always.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你知道这种和平意味着什么吗？
Do you have any idea what this peace means?
它意味着我们的家乡没了…
It means our homes are gone...
所有的…
...all of them...
永远消失了
...forever.
我听说这儿有一些仇视和平协议的人
Heard I could find some treaty haters here.
我来对地方了吗？
I come to the right place?
当然了
You certainly have.
大家跟这个人打个招呼吧 他的职责是…
Everyone say hello to a man who spends his days...
在皇室里为伟大的国王效力
...in the loyal service of our good king.
“曾经”
"Spent."
那些日子一去不复返了
Those days are over.
我已经受够了那个混蛋的谎言
I'm done listening to that bastard's lies.
他或许高居王座 但是他不是国王…
He may sit on a throne, but he ain't no king...
至少不是我的国王
...least not of mine.
好吧 如此说来…
Well, then...
欢迎来到反政府组织 兄弟
...welcome to the resistance, brother.
我希望你有话要说
I hope you're here to talk.
你想知道什么？
What do you wanna know?
求您…
Please...
无论诺克提斯身在何处 保佑他的安全
...wherever Noctis is, keep him safe.
我别无他求
That is all I ask.
你向哪个神祈祷？
To what god do you pray?
你 命运的囚徒
You, the slave of fate and destiny.
放弃你的祈祷吧
Abandon your prayers.
神不会听的
The gods do not listen.
格拉乌卡将军 你为什么会在这儿？
General Glauca. Why are you here?
你这么聪明 肯定不会相信这次和平谈判
You are far too clever to have ever believed in this peace.
真可惜你见不到你挚爱的诺克提斯 你还有别的使命
Pity you couldn't see your beloved Noctis. You have another purpose.
-我来这儿不是为了尼夫海姆 -不是
-I'm not here for Niflheim. -No.
你来这儿是为了我
You are here for me.
你？
You?
我不明白
I do not understand.
明天你就会明白的
Come tomorrow, you will.
（签字仪式当天）
尼夫海姆一行已经离开酒店
Niflheim contingent has left the hotel.
还有不到三个小时 仪式就要开始了
Less than three hours until the ceremony.
加强城堡守卫
Bolster the Citadel guard.
尼克斯 公主和你在一起吗？
Nyx, is the princess with you?
没有
No.
我在守卫城堡
I'm on duty at the Citadel.
那些尼夫海姆人已经出发前往仪式
Well, the Niffs just left for the ceremony.
她没有和他们在一起
And she wasn't with them.
-归航信标？ -是的，现在发送坐标
-A homing beacon? -Yeah, I'll send the coordinates now.
你能为我定位吗？
Can you pinpoint a location for me?
可以 但是听起来像是追着野鹅到处乱跑
Sure, but it sounds like a wild-goose chase.
我猜你有大把的时间 是吗？
Guess you got some free time on your hands, huh?
是的 不管怎样吧
Guess I do, for better or worse.
这些坐标都是在因索莫尼亚以南 二十英里的地方
Those coordinates are about 20 miles south of Insomnia.
城墙之外
Outside the Wall.
克劳去这些地方干什么？
What the hell was Crowe doing all the way out there?
不，不… 他们派她去…
No, no. They sent her to--
我需要你再帮我一个忙 皮尔纳
I need another favor, Pelna.
在雷达上把这些坐标都调出来 告诉我你发现了什么
Pull those coordinates up on the radar and let me know what you find.
收到 你觉得这事关重大吗？
On it. You're thinking this is all a big deal now, huh?
是的 不容忽视
Yeah, too big to ignore.
-对不起，先生 -嘿，嘿，嘿
-Excuse me, sir. Excuse me. -Hey, hey, hey.
-等一下 -停下
-Whoa, wait a minute. -Stop right there.
听好了 这里不仅仅是城门守卫
Listen up. This is not the gate watch.
这里是城市的核心 我们国王的家
This is the heart of our city, the home of our king.
仪式不容中断
The ceremony must not be disturbed.
要迅速地、悄悄地摆平一切威胁
Neutralize any threat quickly and quietly.
明白吗？
Is that understood?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
剑队成员呼叫 你在吗，长官？
Glaive to command. Are you there, captain?
紧急呼叫
Urgent.
该死的 德劳托斯
Damn it, Drautos.
重大发现，尼克斯 在这个位置有一整队飞艇
Jackpot, Nyx. There's a whole fleet of airships sitting at that spot.
-尼夫海姆 -是的，看起来…
-Niflheim. -Yup, and from the looks of it...
我觉得他们在准备作战
...I'd say they're headed to war.
-队长在哪儿？ -应该在城堡
-Where's the captain? -Should be at the Citadel.
他的呼叫器没有应答
There's no answer on his frequency.
我不知道 现在肯定忙着护送任务
I don't know, must have his hands full with the escort detail.
皮尔纳，最后帮个忙 我需要你启动王者之剑
Pelna, one last favor. I need you to prep the Glaive for action.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
你想要不经队长许可 擅自行动？
You wanna deploy without the captain's order?
相信我 动手吧
Trust me. Just get it done.
等一下 我该怎么跟他们说…？
Wait, what am I supposed to tell--?
后退 剑队队员
Stand down, Glaive.
仪式还有两个小时就要开始
The ceremony is in less than two hours.
我们必须做好准备
We must make ready.
很好
Very well.
陛下
Your Majesty.
一位王者之剑队员在此
A man of the Kingsglaive is here, sire.
要求见您
He demands an audience.
“要求”？
"Demands"?
-陛下，求您 -等一下
-Your Majesty, please. -Halt.
请下令启动王者之剑
Give the order to deploy the Glaive.
是你
You.
城墙以南二十英里 尼夫海姆军队已经做好了进攻的准备
A Niflheim fleet makes ready for war 20 miles to the south.
帝国的部队
An imperial fleet.
他们挟持了公主
And they have the princess.
克拉鲁斯 在签约室外增派守卫
Clarus, post guards outside the treaty room.
这样做将被视为对和平缺乏信心
It will be seen as a lack of faith in the peace.
我们应该避免如此
Which we all harbor.
照做吧
See it done.
我们也许还要 把艾尔德卡普特皇帝置于监禁之下
We may well have to take Emperor Aldercapt into custody.
监禁他？
Detain him?
这绝对等同于再次宣战
That would go beyond a new declaration of war.
我们仍处在战争状态，克拉鲁斯
We are still at war, Clarus.
还有你，尼克斯·乌尔里克
And you, Nyx Ulric.
王者之剑多快能够部署？
How soon can the Kingsglaive deploy?
谨候命令，随时都可以
On your word, at once.
那就去吧
Go, then.
救出露娜
Save Luna.
如果这是调虎离山呢？
What if this is a diversion?
不太可能
Not likely.
戴涅布莱的公主在飞艇上
Tenebrae's princess is onboard.
我们有两件任务
We've got two jobs.
救公主
Save her.
阻止尼夫海姆的飞艇 飞临因索莫尼亚
And stop those Niff ships from flying on Insomnia.
我们分组行动
We go in teams.
标准的渗透和拔除行动
Standard infiltrate and extract.
尼克斯，你来指挥，我们听命
Nyx, you command. We'll follow.
王者之剑并肩作战 无论有没有指挥官
The Glaive stands together, captain or no.
为了温暖
For hearth.
还有家园
And home!
距离这项历史性的停战协议的签署 还有不到二十分钟
We are less than 20 minutes away from the signing of this historic treaty.
我接到国王的命令展开部署
I received word of the king's order to deploy.
我来对付城里的事情
I'll see to matters in the city.
你有你的任务 而且并不轻松
You have your mission, and it won't be easy.
目标有两个
The objective is two-fold.
营救人质 阻止敌人的前进
Secure the hostage, and stay the enemy advance.
要小心
Just be careful.
一位剑队成员已经因公主而牺牲
One Glaive already died for this princess.
尼夫海姆不会轻易把她交出来的
Niflheim won't give her up easily.
第二组
Team Two.
我的天
Oh, man.
快点，尼克斯！
Hurry up, Nyx!
救命！
Help!
这边来
Over here.
准备进入甲板下
Preparing to head below deck.
没有命令，不要和敌人正面接触
Do not engage the enemy until instructed.
庆祝仪式仍在进行
The ceremony is underway.
我们等着看尼夫海姆要如何玩
Let's wait and see how Niflheim plays this.
王者之剑已经渗透进敌舰
The Kingsglaive have infiltrated the ships.
一切按计划进行
So everything's going according to plan.
乌尔里克报告 六艘尼夫海姆飞艇正飞往因索莫尼亚
Ulric reporting. Six Niflheim airships confirmed inbound for Insomnia.
尼克斯，这不像是一支作战舰队
Nyx, this doesn't feel like a war fleet.
我应该是找到她了 这里有一扇有守卫的门
I think I might've found her. I got a guarded door here.
两个尼夫海姆的甲兵看守 我该怎么办？
Two Niff MTs. What's the plan?
原地待命
Hold position.
到达指定地点 目标很有可能就在附近
Arrived at destination. High possibility of target in the vicinity.
解救人质
Proceed to secure.
那就必须动手
It's going to mean a fight.
小点声 不要闹大
Keep it quiet and keep it confined.
佩尔纳，你可以接敌了 但是要小点声
Pelna, you're clear to engage. But keep it quiet.
我这就去
I'm on my way.
请原谅我来迟了
Forgive my delay.
有一些意料之外的麻烦
A bit of unforeseen trouble.
希望不是什么大麻烦
Nothing too vexing, I hope.
只是一个小贼而已
A simple theft, nothing more.
贼胆包天 居然偷到国王头上
A daring thief, to steal from the king.
也许魔法城墙和城堡大门 也不能保证一切安全
Perhaps magical walls and castle gates do not keep all things safe.
也许吧
Perhaps.
不过不要紧 偷走的很快都要被归还
But no matter. That which was taken will soon be returned.
难以置信
Impressive.
你是王者中沉着的典范
You are a paragon of kingly composure.
但是我必须发问
But I must ask...
你何以如此确定呢？
...how can you be so sure?
因为这件东西并不仅仅是装饰品
Because this thing is no mere trinket.
它有自己的意志
It possesses a will all its own.
足以打破任何盗贼的束缚
Enough to break any thief's grasp.
听起来确实是一件不错的奖品
That sounds a very fine prize indeed.
该死的，不是现在
Not now, damn it.
给我的？ 你太客气了
For me? You shouldn't have.
目标确认 她一切安好
Target confirmed. She's unharmed.
陛下，剑队找到了公主
The Glaives have recovered the princess, Your Majesty.
你找到那个贼了吗？
Have you found your thief?
找到了
We have.
被偷走的东西完好无损
And what was stolen remains intact.
大好的消息
Joyous news.
这下我就放心了
I am relieved to hear it.
告诉我
Tell me...
在你的帝国里
...how heavy a sentence...
偷窃将要面对怎样的刑罚？
...does the crime of theft carry in your empire?
最重的刑罚之一
Among the heaviest.
不过…
Although there is one...
有一个例外
...exception.
这里将要乱成一片了
Things are about to get ugly over here.
佩尔纳，快离开 这是个圈套
Pelna, get out of there. It's a trap.
-是什么？ -一条有趣的古老法律
-What is that? -A curious old law...
在边疆地区仍然有效
...I still permit in the outlands.
如果盗贼能逃脱追捕
A thief who escapes his captor...
他就不必再为自己的罪行负责
...can no longer be held to account for his crime.
这是对受害者的警告
A warning to the victim.
不要示弱 以免放松正义之手
Never show weakness, lest you forgo the hand of justice.
不，尊敬的国王
Oh, no, good king.
并非如此
Far from it.
协议已经被呈在桌上
The treaty is now on the table.
这个历史性时刻进入倒计时
The countdown begins to this historical moment.
这是对正义之手的警告
It is a warning to the hand of justice itself...
永远不要松开握紧的拳头
...never to loose its grip.
第一组，保护外围
Unit One, secure the perimeter.
第二组，原地守卫
Unit Two, stand your ground.
佩尔纳
Pelna.
戴涅布莱公主安全…
One Tenebrae princess, safe and--
快走
Come on.
水晶 他们是冲着水晶来的
The crystal. They're after the crystal.
甲板下面出事了
There's something going on below deck.
这艘飞艇飞不到因索莫…
The ship's not going to make it to Insom--
你…
You....
出了什么事？
What's going on?
因索莫尼亚正在遭受攻击
Insomnia is under attack.
是谁把你带来的？
Who brought you here?
-格拉乌卡将军 -你是诱饵
-General Glauca. -You were bait.
我们到这里来 也是他们的计划的一部分
Us coming here was all part of their plan.
目标被营救 请求准许撤退
Target secured. Request permission to withdraw.
准许 去…
Granted. Get to--
水晶是不会为你效劳的
The crystal will not serve you.
也不会为你
Nor you...
我要把它带离这座被诅咒的城市
...once I take it from this accursed city.
我来不是为了水晶
It's not the crystal I'm here for.
城墙没有了
The Wall. It's gone.
撤退 这是个圈套
Fall back. It's a trap.
到底是怎么回事？
What the hell is going on?
叛徒
Traitors.
你怎么了？
What's got into you?
来吧，趁着还有机会快撤
Come, we must escape while we can.
不，克拉鲁斯
No, Clarus.
恐怕逃跑这条路已经走不通了
I fear escape is no longer an option.
格拉乌卡将军
General Glauca.
你能坚持住吗？
Can you make it up? Can you stand?
卢彻！
Luche!
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
皇家学院教授驾驶吗？
They teach piloting back at the royal academy?
交给我吧
Give me that.
老朋友 我已经很久没有与你并肩战斗了
Been a long time since I fought at your side, old friend.
是的
Yes...
但这次的战斗不是你的
...but this time it is not your fight.
如果你想离开 现在就走吧
If you wish to leave, go now.
抛下我的国王？ 绝不
And abandon my king? I think not.
另外，我们的魔法都系与你一身
Besides, our magic is bound to you.
如果你倒下，路西斯就完了
If you fall, Lucis falls.
那就让我们再次战斗吧
Then let us once more into the fray...
老朋友
...old friend.
你必须带我去见雷吉斯王
You must take me back to King Regis.
你疯了吗？ 因索莫尼亚是战场
Are you out of your mind? Insomnia's a war zone.
我有一个责任 不能忘记
I have a duty. I cannot neglect it.
-是啊，这种话我早就听过了 -那你应该知道，我们必须抓紧
-Yeah, I heard all that before. -Then you know we must hurry.
抓紧做什么？ 找死吗？
Hurry to do what? Get yourself killed?
我不害怕死亡
I do not fear death.
无畏公主的举动就免了吧
Enough with all this brave princess act.
还是祈祷这东西能飞到目的地吧
Just pray this thing will make the trip.
克拉鲁斯
Clarus.
我想一切都在照计划进行
Well, I daresay everything has proceeded according to plan.
-不是吗？ -确实如此
-No? -So it has.
我们已经破坏了城墙
We have broken the Wall.
现在只剩下摧毁这座城市了
All that remains is to break the city.
我们应该走了吧？
Shall we take our leave, then?
马上就要日落了
The sun will soon set.
我们不必在这里目击黑夜的恐怖
We need not be here to witness the terrors of the night.
神圣水晶
The crystal.
你飞得太快了 我们必须降落
You're going too fast. We have to land.
-你得再容我一会儿 -没有时间了，我自己去
-You're gonna have to give me a minute. -There is no time. I will go on my own.
你的衣服下面藏着翅膀吗？ 魔法是没用的
You got wings underneath that dress? You can't use magic.
不是一切奇迹都要靠魔法
Not all miracles are made by magic.
我不害怕死亡
I do not fear death.
我所怕的是 什么也不做，因而失去一切
What I fear is doing nothing and losing everything.
没办法
Oh, come on.
殿下，这个奇迹靠的还是魔法
You can thank magic for that miracle, Your Highness.
到了清算的时候了
The reckoning is at hand.
新时代的曙光就在眼前
Dawn of a new age.
你已经拿到了水晶 你还想从我这拿走什么？
You have the crystal. What more would you take from me?
路西斯之戒
The Ring of the Lucii.
我失去了我的母亲、我的国家 我与生俱来的权力
I lost my mother, my country, my birth-right.
尼夫海姆是我唯一的希望
Niflheim was the only life left to me.
但这一切都是为了它
But all of that was for this.
这枚戒指现在属于我了
The ring belongs to me now.
侧耳听吧，古时的路西斯众王 我是雷夫斯·诺克斯·弗洛雷
Hear me, Lucian kings of old, for I am Ravus Nox Fleuret...
世间唯我配得拥有你们的能力
...and none is more worthy of your power than I.
不…为什么？
No. Why?
你们为什么拒绝我？
Why do you refuse me?
当心
Look out.
快，从这出去
Quickly, through here.
这里通往一条秘密通道
This leads to a hidden passageway.
沿着通道走
Follow it.
离开之后 前往艾尔提夏
Once you are away, make for Altissia.
诺克提斯在那里等着你们
Noctis awaits you there.
-陛下 -你早知道这些事将要发生…
-Your Majesty. -You knew this was coming--
是的，但只有这样 才能让他们的怒气转离诺克提斯
Yes. But it was the only way to draw their wrath from Noctis.
这就是我们的王吗？
Is that the way of our king?
牺牲路西斯众子来救他自己的命？
Sacrifice Lucian sons to save his own?
是为了救这个世界
To save the world.
把露娜安全送到艾尔提夏
See Luna safely to Altissia.
这不是国王向剑队发出的命令
This is not an order from a king to his Glaive.
这是一个男人向另一个男人的恳求 拜托，尼克斯·乌尔里克，保她安全
This is a plea from one man to another. Please, Nyx Ulric, keep her safe.
为了所有人的未来
For the future of all.
未来？
The future?
给
Here.
拿着
Take this.
是时候把它交给别人保管了
It is time it passed to another's keeping.
不，求你住手
No, please. Stop.
-回来 -求你了，别离开我们
-Get back. -Please. Don't leave us.
我知道 你的母亲与我有同样的企盼
I know your mother would wish the same as me.
就是你和诺克提斯幸福地生活
That you and Noctis live happily.
你被囚禁这么多年 都因我的失败
All those years captive because I failed you.
但这次不会了
Not again.
紧锁的大门再也不能捆绑你的命运
Locked doors will seal your fate no longer.
雷吉斯国王
King Regis....
我们的希望系于你的身上 尼克斯·乌尔里克…祝你成功
Our hope goes with you now, Nyx Ulric. Godspeed.
看啊，路西斯的王
Behold the King of Lucis...
躲在宝贵的城墙后面 积累着平安
...who hoarded tranquility within his precious walls.
你的平安去哪了，陛下？
Where is your tranquility now, king?
你的平安来了 靠的是钢铁的猛然落下
Here is your peace, by steel's swift descent.
快走
Go.
不，我们必须快点离开这儿
No. We must get away from here.
这才是你的国王的意愿
It is what your king wanted.
露娜弗雷亚带着戒指逃跑了
Lady Lunafreya has escaped with the ring.
马上找到她
Find her at once.
她不能离开这座城市
She is not to leave the city.
-乌尔里克呼叫指挥官，队长，回话 -附近一架监控摄像头…
-Ulric to command. Come in, captain. -Footage of the perpetrators...
拍下了罪犯的影像
...was captured by a nearby surveillance camera.
以下是六名嫌犯的图像
Here are images of the six suspects.
其中一人被确认为加拉哈难民 利波特斯·奥斯提姆
One has been identified as Galahdian refugee, Libertus Ostium...
前路西斯王者之剑成员
...a former member of the Lucian Kingsglaive.
嘿，起来
Hey, come here. Come here.
我来救你 你没事了
I got you, I got you. You're all right.
你没事了
You're okay.
没事了
It's fine.
我们自由了
We're free.
我们现在自由了
We're free now.
我们自由了？ 你这是什么意思？
We're free? What do you mean, "We're free"?
帝国…有承诺
The empire. They promised.
这个地区是我们的
This district's ours.
是我们这些难民的
All the refugees.
这是我们的新家园
It's our new home.
-帝国？你投靠了尼夫海姆？ -给你
-The empire? You went in with Niflheim? -Here.
拿着它 与其他人会合
Take this. Meet up with the others.
你是我们的革命英雄，兄弟
You're the hero of our revolution, brother.
该死
Damn it.
这家伙还不知道他被击中了
This guy just doesn't know when he's beat.
-你会开车吗？ -我可以试试
-Can you drive? -I can try.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
这次飞不回去了，英雄
No warping for you this time, hero.
把方向盘给我 让开
Give me the wheel. Go.
你的魔法没了
You are without your magic.
你也注意到了？ 一定是因为国王死了
You noticed that, huh? It must have died with the king.
你把我的城市搞得一团糟，剑队队员 我告诫过你，不要逞英雄
You're making a mess of my city, Glaive. I thought I told you not to go playing hero.
把飞艇交给我吧
Leave the ship to me.
你还有皇家的事情要办
Looks like you got a royal fare to see to.
出去
Move it.
也许并非所有的奇迹都是出于魔法
Maybe not all miracles are made by magic.
太好了
Oh, great.
你做了什么 惹得这些家伙如此生气？
The hell did you do to piss these things off?
它们追的不是我 而是戒指
It's not me they're after. It's the ring.
那枚戒指有什么特殊的？ 别告诉我未来就靠它了
What's so special about this ring? Don't tell me the future's riding on it.
戴上这枚戒指的人 可以与路西斯人沟通
He who wears the ring communes with the Lucii...
-并驾驭强大的力量 -什么样的力量？
-...and commands great power. -What kind of power?
禁忌的力量 很久以前被封在这枚戒指中
A forbidden one. Sealed within the ring, long ago.
旧城墙 我以为那只是睡前故事
The Old Wall. I thought that was just a bedtime story.
我可以担保 那不是睡前故事
I can assure you it is not.
但路西斯人只将这种力量 交与他们认为配得的人
But the Lucii grant their power only to those they deem worthy.
所以刚才那个戴上戒指的人…
So that guy who tried it on back there...
我猜他们认为他不配
...I guess he wasn't deemed worthy.
那是我哥哥
That was my brother.
这十二年改变了雷夫斯
These 12 years have changed Ravus.
他痴迷于过去 迷失在对权力的贪欲中
He is bound by the past, and lost in his lust for power.
它们是怎么找到我们的？
How the hell did they find us?
你的发卡被它们追踪 把它给我
Your hairpin. They're tracking it. Give it to me.
我曾有一个小妹妹 它在帝国入侵时被害
I had a little sister once. She was killed when the empire came.
我救不了她
I couldn't save her.
那时的我 就像现在一样无助
I was as helpless then as I am now.
我无法让她看到自己向往的未来
I couldn't show her the future she wanted.
真正的力量 是无法被那些寻求它的人发现的
True power is not something that is found by those who seek it.
它会找到配得上拥有它的人
It is something that comes to those who deserve it.
你的妹妹也希望你能看到未来
Your sister wanted you to see a future as well.
任何人对他们所爱的家人 都有同样的希望
Anyone would wish the same for family they love.
你是不会放过任何机会的，是吧？
You don't pull any punches, do you?
我在这
I'm over here.
听见了吗？ 我重复一遍…我是德劳托斯
Do you hear me? Repeat, this is Drautos.
能听得见吗？ 完毕
Can you hear me? Over.
你真会挑时候啊，队长
Your timing's impeccable, captain.
如果真有路西斯人
If the Lucii are real...
他们确实不在乎 自己的城市被撕碎
...they sure don't seem to mind their city getting torn apart.
你要重新归队 明白吗？
You're to rendezvous and regroup. Understood?
也许没那么容易，队长
Might not be so easy, captain.
也许你还不知道 我的翅膀被剪了
My wings have been clipped, if you didn't know.
乌尔里克，你还好吧？
Ulric. Are you all right?
我还没死 你是想问这个吗，长官？
I'm not dead, if that's what you mean, sir.
尽快前往D区
Head for Section D as soon as you can.
我让营救队准备好
I'll have an evacuation team ready.
看来我们不能在城门见面了
Don't suppose you could meet me at the gate.
我确实很想离开这座城市
I'd kind of like to get the hell out of this city.
帝国的军队控制了所有出口 没有能够冲出去的地方
Imperials hold all exits. There's no way through.
我们在D区见面
I'll meet you at Section D.
在此之前切断一切无线电联络 你要保证到达那里
Cut all radio contact until then. And make sure you get there.
这是一次亲密约会，长官
It's a date, sir.
没有回头路了
Ain't no turning back now.
状况报告
Status report.
乌尔里克杀死了一些人
Ulric killed some good men.
-戒指呢？ -还没拿到
-What about the ring? -We don't have it yet.
我是格拉乌卡 雷吉斯国王死了
This is Glauca. King Regis is dead.
戒指即将前往D区
The ring is on its way to Section D.
我们必须找到戒指 实现我们的目标
We must recover the ring to realize our goal.
如果乌尔里克或是公主出手阻止 那就干掉他们
If Ulric or the princess get in the way, take them out.
夺回我们的温暖与家园
Reclaim our hearth and home.
“温暖与家园”？
"Hearth and home"?
利波特斯，回话
Libertus, come in.
你在哪？你没事吧？
Where are you? Are you all right?
我很好
I'm fine.
我正在回基地的路上
On the way back to base now.
我们需要你前往D区的交叉路口
We need you to head to the junction in Section D.
我们将与另一组人会合 把那个地方打扫干净
We're gonna join with another unit, make a clean sweep of the place.
我们离革命胜利只差一步了
We're one step away from realizing this revolution.
不要让普鲁维亚白白死去
Let's not let Pruvia's death be in vain.
我们等着你，英雄
We'll be waiting for you, hero.
-在我说“安全”以前不要动 -明白
-Don't move until I say it's safe, all right? -I won't.
乌尔里克报告
Ulric, reporting.
我把公主带来了
I have the princess.
她活的好好的
She's alive and well.
-不！ -快离开
-No! -Get out of here.
你还真能打呀，尼克斯 这一点我承认
You've got some fight in you, Nyx, I'll give you that.
快跑
Run. Now.
我没想到 你身中一枚空尖弹头，居然还能动
I can't believe you're still moving with that hollowpoint in you.
空尖弹头撕裂克劳体内的时候 她只能惨叫
All Crowe could do was scream, when one tore her insides apart.
-你为什么要这么做？ -因为王者之剑什么也不是
-Why'd you do it? -Because the Kingsglaive is nothing.
作一个老家伙的炮灰
An old man's battle fodder...
为了因索莫尼亚的战争而死
...sent to die in Insomnia's war...
而我们的家园却在枷锁之中
...while our homes are bound and shackled.
尼夫海姆夺去了你的家园
Niflheim took your home.
夺去了我们所有人的家园
Took all our homes!
任何事都不能改变这一切
Nothing will ever change that.
你永远不够聪明
You never were too smart.
你本来可以在帝国拥有崭新的未来
You could've had a new future with the empire.
你无处可逃了，公主
There's nowhere to run, princess.
戒指
The ring.
把它给我
Give it to me.
如此多人 为了这样一件小东西而死
So many dead over so simple a thing.
为什么？为了什么？
But why? For what?
力量
Power.
无尽的力量 像你这种人是无法驾驭的
Untold power, beyond the control of someone like you.
力量
Power....
队长
Captain.
尼克斯
Nyx.
一切都结束了 恶魔已经被释放
It's over. The daemons are unleashed.
路西斯沦陷了
Lucis is fallen.
交出戒指
Surrender the ring.
想把自己的想法告诉那些国王吗？
Plan on giving those kings a piece of your mind, princess?
记得吗？你在这里还有未尽的使命
You got a destiny to take care of here, remember?
另外，有没有人告诉你
Besides, didn't anyone tell you?
我才是这里的英雄
I'm the hero around here.
现身吧，路西斯的众王
Show yourselves, kings of Lucis.
你呼求这个世界的未来，凡夫俗子
You call upon the wards of this world's future, mortal.
如果你贪恋我们的力量 就必须首先经受我们的审判
And if you come lusting for our power, you must first stand in our judgment.
你们要旁观因索莫尼亚焚烧到几时？
How long will you do nothing whilst Insomnia burns?
老的少的 无论你们是谁
Old or new, or whatever it is.
筑起你们的城墙
Summon your Wall.
你不能命令我们
You do not command us.
你根本就不是皇室血脉
Yours is not even royal blood.
保护你们的城市 根本不是我们的职责
It does not fall to us to guard your city.
人类是愚蠢的生物
Man is a fool creature...
紧紧抓住过去 对未来畏缩不前
...clinging to his past and cowering from his future.
为了已经逝去的日子而白费力气
Wasting his strength on bygone days.
你们又有什么未来？
And what future are you wards of?
太短视了
So shortsighted.
并且被咒诅 永远不能超越其上
And cursed never to rise above it.
等一下
Wait.
我见过这个勇敢的灵魂准备做什么
I have seen what this brave soul is prepared to do.
他也想保护未来
He, too, seeks to safeguard the future.
陛下
Your Majesty.
好吧，年轻的国王 我们将考量你的武士的价值
Very well, young king. We will weigh your warrior's worth.
但我们的恩惠并不廉价
But our boon does not come cheap.
代价是一条生命 他的、或是她的
The cost is a life. His or hers.
不
No.
去你的力量吧
To hell with your power.
我不是为此而来的
I'm not here for it.
我只是来告诉你们 你们不是王
I only came to tell you, you are no kings.
你的价值已经被考量 结论是不够格
Your worth has been weighed and found wanting.
燃烧吧
Now burn.
你将失去那宝贵的戒指
You're going to lose your precious ring.
但拯救它还为时未晚
But it's not too late to save it.
你要用它交换生命吗？
You mean to barter for your life.
不
No, no.
我的生命不算什么
My life is nothing.
给那些希望看到未来的人一个未来
Giving a future to those who want to see it...
这才是最重要的
...is everything.
你并不害怕 即使那个未来已经注定灭亡
You do not fear, even if that future is doomed.
如果这份感情并非虚假 那么也许你还有些价值
If that sentiment is not false, perhaps you are worthy.
我们将授予你我们的光
We will grant you our light.
但是你要知道 太阳升起之后，它就将消失
But know it will set when the sun rises.
为此付出的代价将是你的生命
And the price for it will be your life.
你们可真会讨价还价
You guys drive a hard bargain.
我在哪签字？
Where do I sign?
等我慢慢习惯吧
I could get used to this.
尼克斯
Nyx....
-对不起 -不必
-I'm sorry. -Don't be.
你救了我
You saved me.
现在我欠你的
Now I owe you.
换换也好
For a change.
我需要你再帮一个忙
I'm gonna need another favor.
这位是露娜弗雷亚·诺克斯·弗洛雷 我们的王子未来的新娘
Meet Lunafreya Nox Fleuret, our prince's beloved bride-to-be.
她的手中掌握着这个世界的未来
And she has the future of the world in her hands.
保护她的安全 带她离开因索莫尼亚
Keep her safe, get her out of Insomnia.
差点忘了 你需要这个
Oh, I almost forgot. You'll need this.
代我向诺克提斯王子致意
Give Prince Noctis my regards.
从现在开始 利波特斯将照顾你
Libertus will take care of you from here.
一路平安，殿下
Have a safe journey, Your Highness.
-你怎么办？ -你要干什么？
-What will come of you? -What the hell are you doing?
遵循众王的命令
Following the kings' orders.
我会把戒指交给诺克提斯
I will see the ring to Noctis.
未来将会平安 我发誓
The future will be safe. I swear it.
你想靠拳头杀出城吗？ 留着吧
Planning on punching your way out of the city? Keep it.
-现在我们扯平了 -不
-Now we're even. -No.
等你回到加拉哈在算账
We'll settle up once you're back in Galahd.
我和其他所有人等着你
Me and everyone else will be waiting for you.
全靠你了
I'm counting on you...
英雄
...hero.
-系好安全带，公主 -我的命在你手中
-Buckle up, princess. -My life is in your hands.
路西斯人的力量又回来了
So, the power of the Lucii returns.
没关系 你没有时间了
No matter. You are out of time.
为了你，我可以挤一些时间
For you, I'll make some.
你有什么希望？
What can you hope to do?
一人对付整个帝国
One man against an empire.
对付众恶魔
Against the daemons.
没有城墙保护 你怎么拯救因索莫尼亚？
How will you save Insomnia with no wall to protect you?
你完全错了 我不是为了拯救因索莫尼亚而战
You've got it all wrong. I'm not fighting to save Insomnia.
这就是强大的旧城墙
So this is the might of the Old Wall.
不可思议 真的不可思议
Marvelous. Truly marvelous.
你为什么要这么做？
Why'd you do it?
路西斯、尼夫海姆
Lucis. Niflheim.
重要的不是为谁而战 而是为了什么
It isn't who we fight for that matters, only what.
我们为了家园而战 这才是我们的忠诚所在
We fight for our homes. That is where our allegiance lies.
这种景象难得一见
That's not something you see every day.
多么可惜的浪费
Oh, such a pitiable waste.
这些漂亮的街道 变成丑陋的废墟
All those beautiful city streets, all laid to unsightly ruin.
-我要返回尼夫海姆 -这么快？
-I will return to Niflheim. -So soon?
神圣水晶已经是我们的了
The crystal is ours.
把这里的事弄完
Finish this...
让恶魔们随意处置吧
...and see the daemons disposed of.
谨遵圣命
As you command.
多么可惜的浪费
Such a pitiable waste.
你怎能为帝国卖命？
How could you serve the empire?
他们都做了些什么！
After everything they did?
我不怪他们 夺得别人的馈赠
I do not fault them for taking what was given.
我怪罪那些馈赠他们的人
I fault the man who gave it.
那个躲在城墙之后的人
The man who cowered behind his wall...
抛弃了我们 只为保住他的王位和儿子
...and abandoned us to save his throne and his son.
把戒指给我 我们的家园将重获自由
Give me the ring, and our homes will be free again.
皇帝承诺如此
The empire has promised it.
在这个承诺上 我看不到什么未来
I don't see much of a future on the other side of that promise.
别作傻瓜
Don't be a fool.
救救你的朋友们吧
Save your friends.
也让你死去的妹妹安息
Give your dead sister peace.
否则你为什么而战？
What do you fight for if not that?
坐稳了 前面很颠簸
Hang on. This could get bumpy.
德劳托斯
Drautos.
给，你来开车
Here, take the wheel.
油门踩到底！
Floor it!
-利波特斯！ -踩住油门别放
-Libertus! -Just keep your foot on the gas.
你没事吧？
You're all right?
我等着你，英雄
I'll be waiting for you, hero.
你那众王的力量怎么了？
What of your kings' power now?
他们交给你的重担 你根本担不起
They've given you a burden you cannot hope to bear.
我曾经告诉你
I told you before.
仅凭愿望 是无法赢得战争的
Just wanting doesn't win wars.
为了我的家园的荣耀 我为了一位我所厌恶的国王四处攻杀
For the honor of my home, I fought and killed under a king I loathed.
但是他仍然背弃了我
And still he betrayed me.
他背弃了我们所有人
He betrayed us all.
我们都在为同样的东西而战
We fought for the same thing. All of us.
但你对过去看得太多
But you've looked too long on the past.
对未来完全无视
You're blind to the future.
太容易被猜透了
Predictable.
和你不一样 我从历史中学习
Unlike you, I learn from history.
但你是往事的奴隶
But you're a slave to the past.
一个人的往事是他的荣耀
A man's past is his pride.
不
No.
我的荣耀在于塑造未来
My pride is shaping the future.
看来我要亏欠他许多了
Looks like I'm gonna owe him big.
我们就快到了
We're almost there.
快到了
Almost.
雷吉斯王为了未来 做了他该做的事
King Regis did what he did for the future.
因为他
Because of him...
我们的家园还有希望
...there's still hope for our homes.
希望…
Hope....
这样死去倒也不算太坏
Not the worst way to go.
好好统治吧，年轻的国王
Rule well, young king.
我们该走了
We should move.
这里也不安全
It ain't safe here either.
嘿
Hey.
别担心尼克斯
Don't worry about Nyx.
他会照顾好自己的
He can take care of himself.
走吧
Come on.
不
No.
我们必须分开了
We must part ways here.
什么？
What?
有你这位大英雄为伴 我怎么能秘密前行？
I can hardly travel in secrecy alongside so great a hero.
我也要为尼克斯信守一个承诺
And I, too, have a promise to keep to Nyx.
我祈祷你们俩很快会重逢
I pray you two see each other again soon.
是啊
Yeah.
我也想
Me too.
谢谢你，利波特斯
Thank you, Libertus.
嘿，王后！
Hey, queen!
随时欢迎你们到加拉哈来
You and the king are always welcome in Galahd.
我和尼克斯会等着你们
Me and Nyx will be waiting for you.
已经有很长时间了
It's been some while.
你还记得上一次看见露娜弗雷亚夫人 是在什么时候吗？
Do you remember the last time you saw Lady Lunafreya?
大概十二年前
About 12 years ago.
也就是说 在你八岁的时候？
That would make you 8?
-你们那时还是小孩子 -希望她别抱太大希望
-You were kids. -Hope she hasn't gotten her hopes up.
为什么不？ 你要镇静
Why not? Calm yourself.
见到她时 你别太激动
Try and keep it together when you meet her.
-她想见到一位得体的年轻王子 -你以为我不知道吗？
-She'll expect to see a fine, young prince. -Tell me something I don't know.
我们没有时间扯这些
We don't have time for all that.
但我们谈论的是你的婚礼
But this is your wedding we're talking about, Noc.
这句也算
Knew that too.
你真的需要冷静一下
You really gotta calm down.
“啊哦”是什么意思？
What do you mean, "Uh-oh"?
我想我明白
I think I know.